export const myCourseOutlineData = [
  //Finance course outline
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Introduction ",
    "answer": "Finance is the study of managing and allocating resources, particularly monetary ones. It involves understanding how individuals, businesses, and governments make financial decisions, manage risks, and invest or allocate funds to achieve their goals and objectives"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Inventory Management ",
    "answer": "Inventory management is the process of overseeing and controlling the flow of goods and products within a business. It involves maintaining optimal stock levels, tracking inventory movements, and ensuring timely restocking to meet customer demand while minimizing carrying costs and stockouts."
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Trade Receivable Management",
    "answer": "Trade receivable management involves overseeing and optimizing a company's accounts receivable. It includes strategies for efficient billing, credit terms, collection procedures, and maintaining positive customer relationships. Effective management ensures a steady cash flow and minimizes the risk of bad debts. \r"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Cash Management",
    "answer": "Cash management involves monitoring, controlling, and optimizing the use of cash within a business. It includes activities such as budgeting, forecasting, liquidity management, and optimizing cash flow to meet short-term financial obligations while maximizing returns on excess cash. \r"
    },

  //Staadpro course outline
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Introduction of staadpro",
    "answer": "STAAD, a structural analysis and design software, empowers engineers to analyze and optimize structures. It ensures structural integrity and compliance with international standards, making it an invaluable tool in civil and structural engineering for diverse projects, from buildings to bridges."
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Advancing the structure",
    "answer": "Advancing the structure involves employing innovative techniques and technologies in engineering and construction to enhance design efficiency, improve structural integrity, and meet evolving standards for safety and sustainability."
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Types of structure Staadpro",
    "answer": "STAAD.Pro, a structural analysis and design software, supports various structure types, including buildings, bridges, towers, and industrial structures. It accommodates different materials like concrete and steel. Its versatility allows engineers to model and analyze diverse structures, ensuring robust designs across a range of engineering projects."
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Model generation ",
    "answer": "Model generation, in the context of structural analysis software like STAAD.Pro, involves creating a digital representation of a structure. This process includes defining geometry, assigning material properties, and specifying structural elements, enabling subsequent analysis and design simulations for engineers and architects."
  },

   //VLSI course outline
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "INtroduction to VLSI",
    "answer": "VLSI, or Very Large-Scale Integration, is a field of electronics that involves designing and manufacturing integrated circuits (ICs) with a vast number of transistors and electronic components on a single chip. VLSI technology enables the creation of complex electronic systems, such as microprocessors and memory chips, with high functionality and compact size. It plays a pivotal role in advancing modern computing and electronic devices."
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Front end Design  Flow & Back end  Design Flow",
    "answer": "Front-end design involves conceptualizing and planning the user interface and experience. Back-end design focuses on the server-side logic and database. Design flow integrates these processes for seamless development, from user interface to database functionality."
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Introduction & Importance of HDL",
    "answer": "Hardware Description Language (HDL) is crucial in digital circuit design, allowing engineers to describe and simulate complex hardware structures. HDLs like Verilog and VHDL are vital for efficient communication between designers and electronic design automation tools, facilitating the creation of intricate digital systems."
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "SV Class",
    "answer": "SystemVerilog (SV) is an extension of Verilog, incorporating features for hardware description, verification, and design. It offers object-oriented programming constructs, enhanced data types, and assertions, making it a powerful language for designing and verifying complex digital systems within the hardware description and verification domain."
  },

  //AWS course outline
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Clustering and Virtualization",
    "answer": "Clustering involves grouping multiple servers to work together, enhancing reliability. Virtualization creates virtual instances of resources, optimizing efficiency. Both technologies enhance performance, scalability, and resource utilization in IT infrastructures."
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Cloud Platform Architecture",
    "answer": "Cloud platform architecture refers to the design and structure of a cloud computing environment. It encompasses components like servers, storage, networking, and services, organized to provide scalable, reliable, and efficient solutions for users and applications."
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Cloud Resource Management and Scheduling: ",
    "answer": "Cloud resource management involves efficiently allocating and overseeing computing resources in a cloud environment. Scheduling optimizes the use of these resources, ensuring tasks are executed effectively based on priority, availability, and performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Storage systems",
    "answer": "Storage systems refer to hardware and software solutions designed for the management and retrieval of digital data. These systems can include various technologies like traditional disk storage, solid-state drives, network-attached storage (NAS), and storage area networks (SAN), providing scalable and reliable data storage solutions for diverse applications."
  },

  //HR course outline
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Introduction to HR",
    "answer": "Human Resources (HR) is a vital organizational function managing personnel-related tasks. It involves recruitment, training, benefits administration, and fostering a positive workplace culture to support employee well-being and business success"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Team Management",
    "answer": "Team management involves leading and guiding a group of individuals to achieve common goals. It includes effective communication, fostering collaboration, setting clear expectations, providing support, and promoting a positive team culture for optimal performance."
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Talent Acquisition and Management",
    "answer": "Talent acquisition and management encompass the strategic processes of recruiting, hiring, and developing employees. It involves sourcing top talent, assessing skills, onboarding, and implementing strategies for employee retention and career advancement within the organization."
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Training Management ",
    "answer": "Training management involves planning, organizing, and overseeing training programs for employees. It includes identifying training needs, designing effective programs, delivering content, and evaluating outcomes to enhance skills and knowledge within the organization."
  },

  //Bioinformatics course outline
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Introduction to Bioinformatics",
    "answer": "Bioinformatics integrates biology, computer science, and data analysis to interpret biological information. It involves computational tools to analyze DNA, proteins, and other biological data, enhancing biological research and understanding."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Protein Bioinformatics",
    "answer": "Protein bioinformatics involves the application of computational methods to analyze, interpret, and predict the structure, function, and interactions of proteins. It plays a crucial role in understanding biological processes and drug discovery"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Computational biology",
    "answer": "Computational biology employs computational techniques to analyze biological data, model biological processes, and solve complex biological problems. It merges biology with computer science, utilizing algorithms and simulations to advance research and understanding in genomics, proteomics, and other areas."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Structural bioinformatics",
    "answer": "Structural bioinformatics is a multidisciplinary field that applies computational methods to analyze and model the three-dimensional structures of biological macromolecules, such as proteins and nucleic acids. It plays a crucial role in understanding molecular interactions, drug discovery, and protein engineering."
  },

  //Marketing Management course outline
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "Introduction to marketing management",
    "answer": "Marketing basics involve strategies and activities aimed at promoting and selling products or services. It encompasses market research, product positioning, target audience identification, pricing, promotion, and distribution. Effective marketing is crucial for business success, as it creates awareness, generates demand, and builds customer relationships."
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Marketing Strategy and Planning",
    "answer": "Marketing strategy and planning involve developing a roadmap to achieve business objectives. This includes analyzing the market, identifying target audiences, setting goals, determining a unique value proposition, and selecting appropriate marketing channels. The planning process includes budgeting, creating a timeline, and outlining specific tactics to implement the strategy effectively. Regular evaluation and adjustment ensure adaptability to market changes."
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Digital Marketing",
    "answer": "Digital marketing leverages online platforms for promotion, including social media, SEO, email, and content marketing. It aims to reach target audiences, build brand awareness, and drive engagement for businesses."
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Market Segmentation ",
    "answer": "Market segmentation is the process of dividing a diverse market into distinct groups based on common characteristics. This enables businesses to tailor their marketing strategies to specific segments for more effective communication and targeted offerings."
  },

  //AutoCad Management course outline
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "INTRODUCTION TO DRAWING AND ENGINEERING DRAWING",
    "answer": "Drawing is a creative expression capturing ideas visually, while engineering drawing is a precise form of communication using standardized symbols and conventions to convey technical details for manufacturing and construction."
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "BASIC CONCEPTS TO BE FOLLOWED BEFORE STATING DRAWING",
    "answer": "Before starting a drawing, consider fundamental concepts such as understanding the purpose, defining scale, planning layout, selecting appropriate tools, and ensuring accuracy in measurements for successful execution."
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "ISOMETRIC DRAWING",
    "answer": "Isometric drawing is a three-dimensional representation technique that visually portrays objects in a 3D space. Unlike traditional 2D drawings, isometric drawings maintain equal scale measurements along all axes simultaneously, providing a more realistic view of objects. This method aids in conveying spatial relationships and dimensions accurately"
  },

  //Embedded System Management course outline
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Introduction to Embedded C language ",
    "answer": "Embedded C is a programming language tailored for embedded systems, emphasizing efficiency and hardware-level control. It enables developers to create software for microcontrollers and other resource-constrained devices."
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Memory Organization and mapping",
    "answer": "Memory organization refers to the arrangement of data in a computer's memory. Memory mapping involves assigning addresses to memory locations for efficient storage and retrieval of information."
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Project creation & Coding (Cube IDE)",
    "answer": "To create a project in Cube IDE, open the software, choose a microcontroller, configure peripherals, and set project parameters. "
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Potentiometer & ADC interfacing",
    "answer": "A potentiometer is an adjustable resistor, often used as a voltage divider. Interfacing it with an Analog-to-Digital Converter (ADC) enables digital systems to measure and convert the analog voltage output."
  },

  //Robotics course outline
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "Introduction to robotics",
    "answer": "Introduction to robotics"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Introduction to Arduino Software",
    "answer": "Arduino Software, also known as the Arduino IDE (Integrated Development Environment), is an open-source platform used for programming Arduino boards. It provides a user-friendly interface for writing, compiling, and uploading code."
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Basics of Electronics & Microcontroller",
    "answer": "Electronics involves the study of electrical circuits, components, and systems. Microcontrollers are small integrated circuits that control electronic devices. They combine a processor, memory, and peripherals for various applications."
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Working with Arduino IDE & sensors",
    "answer": "Arduino IDE is a platform for programming Arduino microcontrollers. To use sensors, connect them to the Arduino, write code in the IDE to read sensor data, and upload it to the board."
  },

  //DS course outline
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Introduction to data science ",
    "answer": "Data science is a multidisciplinary field that extracts insights and knowledge from data. It involves statistics, machine learning, and domain expertise to analyze and interpret complex datasets for decision-making."
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "Relational database",
    "answer": "A relational database is a structured collection of data organized in tables, where relationships between data elements are established using keys. It ensures efficient data management and retrieval."
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Applied status",
    "answer": "Applied status\" typically refers to the current stage of a process where someone has submitted an application, such as a job application or a college application, and is waiting for a response or a decision."
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Introduction to machine learning",
    "answer": "Machine learning is a branch of artificial intelligence that enables systems to learn and make predictions without explicit programming. It uses algorithms to analyze data and extract patterns for decision-making."
  },

  //Genetics course outline
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Introduction ",
    "answer": "Genetics is the study of genes, heredity, and variation in living  organisms. It explores the molecular basis of inheritance, DNA structure, and the role of genes in determining traits."
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Human Genome Project",
    "answer": "The Human Genome Project, completed in 2003, mapped and sequenced all human DNA, identifying genes and understanding their functions. This groundbreaking effort advanced genetics, medicine, and biotechnology."
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "DNA vectors",
    "answer": "DNA vectors are small, circular DNA molecules used in genetic engineering to carry foreign genes into host organisms. Common vectors include plasmids and viral vectors, enabling gene manipulation and expression."
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Northern Blotting",
    "answer": "Northern blotting is a molecular biology technique used to study gene expression. It involves transferring RNA molecules from a gel to a membrane, followed by detection using a labeled probe."
  },

  //Digital Marketing course outline
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Introduction to Digital Marketing",
    "answer": "Digital marketing leverages online channels to promote products                   or services, reaching a global audience. Utilizing social media, search       engines, and email, it enhances brand visibility, engagement, and sales."
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "Search Engine Optimisation",
    "answer": "Search Engine Optimization (SEO) is crucial for enhancing online visibility. It involves optimizing content, keywords, and technical aspects of a website to rank higher in search engine results, driving organic traffic and improving online presence."
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "Content Strategy & Media Planning",
    "answer": "Content strategy involves creating, managing, and distributing valuable content to achieve business goals. Media planning focuses on selecting the right channels and scheduling content for optimal reach and impact"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "Content Writing & Copywriting",
    "answer": "Crafting compelling content and persuasive copy requires a mastery of language, creativity, and strategic thinking. These skills converge to engage audiences, build brand presence, and drive desired actions."
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "Social Media Optimisation",
    "answer": "Social Media Optimization (SMO) involves enhancing and managing a brand's online presence through strategic content, engagement, and community building on social media platforms to increase visibility and audience interaction."
  },

  //Andriod Dev course outline
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "Introduction to Android Development",
    "answer": "Overview of Android Os & its Architecture Setting Up the Development Environment Creating the First 'Hello World' App Understanding the Project Structure."
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "Java Essentials for Android",
    "answer": "Classes and Objects Encapsulation, Inheritance and Polymorphism Constructors and Methods."
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "Collections & Exception Handling",
    "answer": "Arrays and Array Lists Exception Handling (Try, Catch, Throw, Throws, Finally) Brief Overview of Other Java Collections (HashMap, HashSet)"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "User Interface (UI)Basics",
    "answer": "XML Layout Files & Views Common UI Elements (Text View, Edit Text, Button, etc) Layouts (Linear Layout, Relative Layout) Handling User Input & Events."
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Activities and Intents",
    "answer": "XML Layout Files & Views Common UI Elements (Text View, Edit Text, Button, etc) Layouts (Linear Layout, Relative Layout) Handling User Input & Events."
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "UI Advanced",
    "answer": "Fragments and their Lifecycle Using Recycler View for Dynamic Lists Customizing UI with Styles and Themes."
  },

   //Security course outline
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Internet Networks",
    "answer": "The internet's history spans its life cycle, from submarine cable maps to diverse networks, topologies, OSI models, TCP/IP implementation, IP addressing, and subnet masking."
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "Operating System Introduction to Ethical Hacking",
    "answer": "Understanding BIOS and OS architectures is crucial for cybersecurity, while exploring hacker types and ethical hacking emphasizes the importance of maintaining robust security measures."
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "Foot Printing & Reconnaissance",
    "answer": "Footprinting in ethical hacking involves discovering a company's details, domain, URLs, servers, registration, IP range, DNS, and locations. This includes traceroute analysis and tracking emails for cybersecurity assessments."
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "Cross Site Scripting",
    "answer": "Persistent XSS occurs when malicious input originates from the website's database, reflected XSS happens when it comes from the victims' request, and DOM-Based XSS exploits vulnerabilities in client-side code instead of server-side code."
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "Scanning Hacking Web Services & Web Applications",
    "answer": "The course covers objectives of network scanning, live host discovery, SNMP, SMTP, and DNS enumeration, open port identification, and service finding. It delves into vulnerability scanning, proxy server usage by hackers, TOR network preference, web server applications, and associated hacking risks like directory traversal, website defacement, and password brute-forcing."
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "SQL Injection Session Hijacking",
    "answer": "The internet's history spans its life cycle, from submarine cable maps to diverse networks, topologies, OSI models, TCP/IP implementation, IP addressing, and subnet masking."
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Denial Of Service",
    "answer": "The Denial of Service (DoS) course covers the various techniques used to disrupt or limit the availability of computer systems, networks, or services. Students will explore the symptoms of a DoS attack, the types of techniques employed by attackers, and the countermeasures to defend against such attacks."
  },

  //Machine Learning course outline
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "Introduction & Installation Python Background, Need & Importance",
    "answer": "The introduction and installation process sets the stage for Python programming, paving the way for writing your first program. Understanding input/output (I/O) operations in Python completes the foundational skills needed for effective coding."
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "Programming Elements Keywords & Variables",
    "answer": "Exploring data types such as numbers and strings in Python, understanding the various operations that can be performed on them, and engaging in hands-on implementation provide a comprehensive approach to mastering Python programming."
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Conditions & Loops Indentation & Scopes",
    "answer": "Understanding indentation and scopes is fundamental for Python code structure. If-else and elif blocks provide conditional branching, while an introduction to loops, including for and while loops, enhances iterative processes. Break and continue statements within loops offer control and customization, contributing to efficient program flow."
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "Data Structures",
    "answer": "Exploring lists, tulips, sets, and dictionaries allows for versatile data structures in Python, where CRUD operations (Create, Read, Update, Delete) play a crucial role in effective data manipulation. Building a Rock Paper Scissors game with console input/output provides a practical application to reinforce understanding and implementation of these data structures."
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "Functions & Exception Handling",
    "answer": "An introduction to functions, including an understanding of positional and keyword arguments, is essential for efficient code structure. Return statements facilitate the output of desired results, while incorporating try, catch, and finally blocks ensures robust error handling and graceful program execution."
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "Add On Topics",
    "answer": "File handling, involving Input/Output (I/O) operations, plays a crucial role in manipulating and managing data. Numpy arrays enhance efficient data handling in Python, enabling advanced numerical operations."
  },

  //AI course outline
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "Introduction & Installation Python Background, Need & Importance",
    "answer": "The introduction and installation process sets the stage for Python programming, paving the way for writing your first program. Understanding input/output (I/O) operations in Python completes the foundational skills needed for effective coding."
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Machine Learning",
    "answer": "Understanding the prediction system is essential, particularly when comparing machine learning to deep learning. In machine learning, there are two main forms: supervised and unsupervised, with regression and classification being crucial techniques within this domain."
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "Introduction of AI",
    "answer": "Understanding the background and need, the introductory phase involves installation, leading to writing the first program in Python and exploring input/output functions."
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "Programming Elements",
    "answer": "It seems there might be a mistake, as the words or context for the sentence you're referring to are missing. Could you please provide the words or context so I can assist you better?."
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "Conditions & Loops",
    "answer": "In AI, understanding indentation, scopes, conditional blocks (if, else, elif), loops (for, while), and utilizing break and continue statements are fundamental concepts in programming logic and flow control.."
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Data Structures",
    "answer": "In AI, learners explore various data structures like lists, tuples, sets, and dictionaries, applying CRUD operations and building games like Rock Paper Scissors using console interactions.."
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Functions & Exception Handling",
    "answer": "An introduction to functions in AI covers positional and keyword arguments, exception handling, and the significance of return statements in optimizing code."
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "Add On Topics",
    "answer": "AI practitioners leverage file handling for I/O operations, manipulate data with NumPy arrays, and analyze case studies to refine algorithms."
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Basics Of AI",
    "answer": "Exploring AG, ML, and DL differences—seeking a Teachable Machine demo to grasp AG's practical application."
  },

  //AR-VR course outline
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "A Brief Overview of Mixed Reality (AR/VR)",
    "answer": "In this section, you will learn about the history of augmented, virtual, and mixed reality as well as their various forms. You will also learn other mixed reality fundamentals."
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Overview of Unity 3D",
    "answer": "Discover the many Unity 3D views and interfaces in this section. Playthrough Mode and Hand Tool will also be clear to you."
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "In-game Items",
    "answer": "This session introduces you to world versus local coordinates, game objects, and dimensions and coordinate systems for 3D modeling."
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "Textures, Materials, and Models",
    "answer": "Overview of 3D objects and models, including how to import models and comprehend materials, textures, and shaders"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "Camera and Lights",
    "answer": "You will learn about lights, halos, directional lights, spotlights, and cookies in this module. After that, you will learn about cameras, their layers, and their anatomy."
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "Writing scripts",
    "answer": "You'll comprehend operators, conditional statements, and scripts. Additionally, techniques, the structure of processes, and particular essential inputs and components will be covered."
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "Prefabricated structures",
    "answer": "An introduction to prefabs would be covered in this module. Additionally, using codes, you will learn about the Structure, Operation, and Deployment of Prefabs."
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Interface with Users",
    "answer": "Discover the basic UI elements and principles, such as world space, screen-space elements, text, buttons, and anchors."
  },

  //Web-dev course outline
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "HTML",
    "answer": "The course encompasses HTML fundamentals, covering introductory concepts, a comprehensive range of HTML tags, and practical hands-on experience using Visual Studio Code to explore HTML5 tags, facilitating a robust foundation in web development."
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "Bootstrap",
    "answer": "The curriculum includes a detailed exploration of web development essentials such as Bootstrap, covering containers, components, carousels, buttons, and various button attributes, providing a holistic understanding of front-end design and functionality."
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Javascript",
    "answer": "The course will cover the fundamentals of web development, including an introduction to JavaScript, ES6, its features, and control statements, offering a comprehensive understanding of programming concepts."
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "Jquery & NodeJS",
    "answer": "The course will cover essential aspects of web development, including teaching JQuery and its integration with JavaScript, an introduction to backend development with Node.js, file handling, and the creation of servers for a comprehensive learning experience."
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "NodeJS & ExpressJS",
    "answer": "The course will cover Node.js Buffer Management alongside Express.js for efficient server creation and establishment using Express."
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "MYSQL & MONGODB",
    "answer": "Introduction to Database includes an overview of SQL, covering DDL, DML, DCL, and TCL operations."
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "React JS",
    "answer": "Learn the foundations of React JS through hands-on exploration of JSX, containers, class components, and functional components."
  },

  //Stock Market course outline
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Introduction to Stock Market Analytics",
    "answer": "This section provides an overview of stock market analytics, emphasizing its role in investment decision-making. Topics include the types of analysis (fundamental, technical, quantitative), key metrics, and the importance of data-driven strategies."
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Data Sources and Preparation",
    "answer": "Participants learn about data sources in the stock market, including historical price data, financial statements, and market indicators. Techniques for cleaning, preprocessing, and organizing data for analysis are covered, ensuring accuracy and reliability."
  }, 
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "Statistical Analysis and Modeling",
    "answer": "Statistical tools and techniques for analyzing stock market data are discussed, including measures of central tendency, volatility, and correlation. Participants explore predictive modeling methods such as time series analysis and machine learning for forecasting stock prices and trends."
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "Technical Analysis and Trading Strategies",
    "answer": "This section focuses on technical analysis techniques, including chart patterns, indicators, and trend analysis. Participants learn how to develop and backtest trading strategies based on technical signals and market patterns."
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "Risk Management and Portfolio Optimization",
    "answer": "Risk management principles for investing in the stock market are introduced, covering concepts such as diversification, asset allocation, and risk-adjusted returns. Portfolio optimization techniques, including modern portfolio theory and risk parity, are discussed to help participants build balanced and efficient investment portfolios."
  },

  //Business Analytics course outline
  {
    "id": 101,
    "question": "Introduction to Business Analytics",
    "answer": "Business analytics involves using data analysis to drive decision-making in business. This section introduces the field's importance, covering descriptive, predictive, and prescriptive analytics, along with essential tools and techniques."
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "question": "Data Collection and Preparation",
    "answer": "This section focuses on ensuring data quality and readiness for analysis. It covers data collection methods, cleaning, preprocessing, and visualization techniques to address issues like missing data and outliers."
  }, 
  {
    "id": 103,
    "question": "Statistical Analysis and Predictive Modeling",
    "answer": "Statistical analysis is crucial for uncovering insights from data. Participants learn basic statistical concepts and predictive modeling techniques such as regression and classification for forecasting and decision-making."
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "question": "Business Intelligence and Data Mining",
    "answer": "Here, participants explore business intelligence tools and data mining techniques to uncover patterns and insights from data, including association rule mining, clustering, and sentiment analysis."
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "question": "Decision Support and Optimization",
    "answer": "Decision support systems and optimization techniques are discussed, focusing on resource allocation, linear programming, simulation modeling, and the challenges of implementing analytics solutions."
  },

  //IOT course outline
  {
    "id": 106,
    "question": "Introduction to IoT",
    "answer": "This section provides an overview of IoT, exploring its definition, applications, and impact on various industries. Participants learn about the interconnected nature of IoT devices and the ecosystem that supports them."
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "question": "IoT Architecture and Components",
    "answer": "Participants delve into the architecture of IoT systems, including sensors, actuators, communication protocols, and IoT platforms. The section covers the roles and interactions of each component in collecting, processing, and transmitting data."
  }, 
  {
    "id": 108,
    "question": "Data Collection and Management",
    "answer": "Techniques for collecting, storing, and managing data generated by IoT devices are discussed. Participants explore topics such as data acquisition, storage solutions (cloud vs. edge), and data processing techniques to derive actionable insights."
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "question": "IoT Security and Privacy",
    "answer": "Security considerations in IoT systems are examined, including device authentication, encryption, and access control mechanisms. Participants learn about potential vulnerabilities and best practices for safeguarding IoT deployments and protecting user privacy."
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "question": "IoT Applications and Case Studies",
    "answer": "This section explores real-world applications of IoT across various domains such as healthcare, transportation, agriculture, and smart cities. Participants analyze case studies to understand how IoT technologies are being implemented to solve practical challenges and improve efficiency and quality of life."
  },

  //Nanoscience course outline
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question": "Introduction to Nanoscience",
    "answer": "This section provides an introduction to nanoscience, covering its definition, scope, and significance in various fields. Participants explore the unique properties of nanomaterials and the principles that govern their behavior at the nanoscale."
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question": "Fundamental Concepts in Nanotechnology",
    "answer": "Participants delve into fundamental concepts in nanotechnology, including quantum mechanics, surface science, and nanoscale fabrication techniques. The section covers the principles underlying the synthesis, manipulation, and characterization of nanomaterials."
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question": "Nanomaterials and Their Properties",
    "answer": "This section explores different types of nanomaterials, such as nanoparticles, nanotubes, and nanocomposites, and their unique properties. Participants learn about size-dependent phenomena, quantum confinement effects, and applications of nanomaterials in various industries."
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question": "Nanotechnology in Medicine and Healthcare",
    "answer": "Participants examine the applications of nanotechnology in medicine and healthcare, including drug delivery systems, medical imaging, and diagnostics. Case studies highlight the role of nanotechnology in advancing treatment modalities and improving patient outcomes."
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question": "Environmental and Energy Applications of Nanotechnology",
    "answer": "This section discusses the environmental and energy applications of nanotechnology, such as water purification, pollution remediation, and renewable energy technologies. Participants explore how nanomaterials and nanodevices are being used to address global challenges in sustainability and clean energy."
  }
];

export const finance = myCourseOutlineData.slice(0, 4);
export const staadpro = myCourseOutlineData.slice(4, 8);
export const vlsi = myCourseOutlineData.slice(8, 12);
export const aws = myCourseOutlineData.slice(12, 16);
export const hr = myCourseOutlineData.slice(16, 20);
export const bioinformatics = myCourseOutlineData.slice(20, 24);
export const marketingmanagement = myCourseOutlineData.slice(24, 28);
export const autocad = myCourseOutlineData.slice(28, 31);
export const embeddedsystem = myCourseOutlineData.slice(31, 35);
export const robotics = myCourseOutlineData.slice(35, 39);
export const datascience = myCourseOutlineData.slice(40, 43);
export const geneticengineering = myCourseOutlineData.slice(43, 47);
export const digitalmarketing = myCourseOutlineData.slice(47, 52);
export const appdev = myCourseOutlineData.slice(52, 58);
export const cybersecurity = myCourseOutlineData.slice(58, 65);
export const machinelearning = myCourseOutlineData.slice(65, 71);
export const ai = myCourseOutlineData.slice(71, 80);
export const arvr = myCourseOutlineData.slice(81, 88);
export const webdev = myCourseOutlineData.slice(88, 95);
export const stockmarket = myCourseOutlineData.slice(95, 100);
export const ba = myCourseOutlineData.slice(100, 105);
export const iot = myCourseOutlineData.slice(105, 110);
export const nanoscience = myCourseOutlineData.slice(110, 115);

